<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic</title>
    <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ihshaish.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ihshaish.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing the Predictivity of Features to Characterise the Search Space</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/icann2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/icann2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating defection in subscription-type markets, empirical analysis from the scholarly publishing industry</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/preprint-defection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/preprint-defection/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Machine Learning Approach to Classifying Construction Cost Documents into the International Construction Measurement Standard</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/icms-preprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/icms-preprint/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FinTech West Talent Showcase Event</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/post/fintechwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/post/fintechwest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FinTech West Talent Showcase Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday 12th October, FinTech West hosted our inaugural FinTech Talent Showcase event, hosted in partnership with the University of Bristol and the University of the West of England. Martin Palmer, Marketing Director at Clarke Willmott, opened the event and welcomed the audience, reflecting on how Clarke Willmott had been involved in the creation of FinTech West, which was originally known as Bristol FinTech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;padding:56.25% 0 0 0;position:relative;&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/video/774469463?h=3ca5c60f9a&amp;amp;badge=0&amp;amp;autopause=0&amp;amp;player_id=0&amp;amp;app_id=58479&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen style=&#34;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;&#34; title=&#34;Fintech West Talent Showcase 2022&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fintechwest.co.uk/news/event-review-fintech-wests-talent-showcase&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Read more on the event&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation &#34;ML, Analytics, Data Science  &amp;  FinTech&#34;.</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/post/rbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/post/rbi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turing Event. Future Space, Bristol Robotics Laboratory, Bristol&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turing Network &amp;amp; RBI Event. Industry and Academics workshop on 21st Sep. to explore collaboration on research, development as well as knowledge exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;strong&gt;Presentation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;responsive-wrap&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1iOrnsQbmGj_ijhicyGc1eit9ypQtOmpiO2A25N3t8xA/edit?usp=sharing&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;960&#34; height=&#34;569&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31st International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks.</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/post/icann-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/post/icann-conf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;31st International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks at UWE.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hosted and organised the 31st International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks at UWE. My undergraduate student, Reece Nicholles, presnted his paper on &amp;ldquo;Problem Classification for Tailored Helpdesk Auto-replies&amp;rdquo; and Rafet Durgut, visiting researcher, on &amp;ldquo;Analysing the Predictivity of Features to Characterise the Search Space&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;markmap&#34; style=&#34;height: 500px;&#34;&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;  - Links
    - [Conference details](https://e-nns.org/icann2022/)
    - [Reece&#39; paper](/publication/icann1/)
    - [Rafet&#39;s paper](/publication/icann2/)&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem Classification for Tailored Helpdesk Auto-replies</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/icann1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/icann1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating wind variability to modelling wind-ramp events using a non-binary ramp function and deep learning models</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/post/sharp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/post/sharp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3International Conference for Sustainable Ecological Engineering Design for Society, SEEDS 2022.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russell Sharp, my MSc Data Science Student, presented his thesis work titled &amp;ldquo;Integrating wind variability to modelling wind-ramp events using a non-binary ramp function and deep learning models&amp;rdquo; at the International Conference for Sustainable Ecological Engineering Design for Society, SEEDS 2022. See &lt;strong&gt;thesis&lt;/strong&gt; (document) and a short &lt;strong&gt;video&lt;/strong&gt; presentation below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;
The forecasting of large and rapid changes in wind power output known as ramp events is crucial for the incorporation of large volumes of wind energy into national electricity grids. Large variations in wind power supply must be compensated by ancillary energy sources which can include fossil fuels along with their associated costs and carbon emissions. Improved prediction of wind power will help to improve the competitiveness of wind energy against non-renewable energy sources, enable the global transition to cleaner fuels and facilitate climate change mitigation. This paper investigates the potential application of Machine Learning methodologies to the task of ramp event prediction. Using a non-binary wavelet transform approach to ramp characterisation, the ability of three Machine Learning models to predict ramp events in the Engie La Haute Borne wind farm dataset is compared. Results indicate that Recurrent Neural Network models show the greatest potential for ramp event forecasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.leedsbeckett.ac.uk/events/conferences/seeds-conference-2022/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Conference details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📚 &lt;strong&gt;Thesis Preview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;responsive-wrap&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1VY-0VA9yFhNgB29ooXc6_vqnf-hrewi_/edit?usp=sharing&amp;amp;ouid=118221652625957228493&amp;amp;rtpof=true&amp;amp;sd=true&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;960&#34; height=&#34;569&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;strong&gt;Watch a brief summary of Sharp&amp;rsquo;s work:&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fMa1BFf7KN0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Interested?&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Please get in touch if you&amp;rsquo;d like exploring further work and development on wind power modelling and prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Task-Oriented Dialogue Systems - Performance vs Quality-Optima, A Review</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/ryan1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/ryan1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>qNoise. A generator of non-Gaussian colored noise</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/qnoise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/qnoise/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AgroSupportAnalytics- A Cloud-based Complaints Management and Decision Support System for Sustainable Farming in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/egypt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/egypt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Synthetic Personalities for Intelligent Autonomous Objects.</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/project3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[internal] VC Inter-dicsiplinary Research Fund UK £25k to explore the design of the new class of ‘intelligent assistants&amp;rsquo; that are appearing in commercial and domestic markets. Aiming to improve usability, user acceptance and user-comprehension wherever intelligent, voice-driven, AI systems are exposed to human users. — &lt;strong&gt;PI&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AgriTech in Egypt.</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;British Council Newton Fund £250k. AgriTech for Egypt - Exploring the application of NLP and Image Processing for an effective decision support system to enhance farmers&amp;rsquo; decision-making, their routine agricultural practices and prevention actions.  &lt;strong&gt;Co-PI leading the Machine Learning research and development&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We partner with the Egyptian Ministry of Agriculture and Al-Fayoum Universty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://agrosupportanalytics.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Further information here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation in Construction</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Innovate UK £1.2M funding to explore the application of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning for Infrastructure Project Performance Benchmarking — &lt;strong&gt;Co-PI leading the AI and ML team and development&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows us that up to half of the money invested in infrastructure delivery could be spent more efficiently. Determined to increase the productivity and value-for-money of transport infrastructure projects, a transformative collaboration of 25 partners together with Government, i3P and the Construction Innovation Hub formed TIES Living Lab.
Using data, technology and Modern Methods of Construction (MMC) within live transport infrastructure projects, the TIES Living Lab will deliver significant value-adding benefits across the transport infrastructure sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results of our first models to automate project benchmarking are provided in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/icms-preprint/&#34;&gt;our preprint&lt;/a&gt;. Models have been trained and systematically evaluated from a dataset of more than 50 thousand descriptions of items retrieved from 24 large infrastructure construction (Highways England) projects across the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ph.D. Projects — Funding from GE Aviation and UWE. - [PI ~£250k].</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/project4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PETER MAYHEW&lt;/strong&gt; (funded by GE AVIATION) works on &amp;ldquo;a new framework to identify a common multilevel structure (event inter-dependency) of maintenance repairs to allow the prediction of the repair outcome of electronic components in avionics. Peter is developing a new framework, MARCONI (eMbeddings frAmework foR Classification Of avioNic repaIrs) based on Word2Vec for a word embedding to model the semantics in language sequence and events recorded in the maintenance records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RYAN FELLOWS&lt;/strong&gt; (funded by ITS and CATE) works on conversational agents; the Task-oriented Dialogue Systems or chatobs in particular. His research focuses on  examining and evaluating the sensitivity of TODS (task-oriented dialogue systems / chatbots) performance to conversational quality attributes, and exploring methods to steer their performance on the basis of optimising attributes’ temporal variability in dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Par@Graph – a parallel toolbox for the construction and analysis of large complex climate networks</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/paragraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/paragraph/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marie-Curie Initial Training Network (ITN) - Learning about Interacting Networks in Climate</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/linc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/linc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Improving our understanding of the Earth´s complex climate phenomena, such as El Niño-Southern Oscillation (ENSO), has a huge economic and social impact for present and future generations, and can underpin advances in areas as diverse as energy, environment, agricultural and marine sciences. Given the complexity of the inter-relations between the subsystems that constitute our climate, it is important to approach the problem from an interdisciplinary perspective. However,there is a great shortage of qualified workforce to perform this task and a major challenge is the education and training of young qualified researchers that can approach climate phenomena from a complex systems point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This requires knowledge from several fields such as physics, dynamical systems theory and computer science, and also requires a detailed understanding of Earth sciences such as meteorology and oceanography. There is also a clear need for improving the coordination and cooperation of the research teams working on these issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://climatelinc.eu/about-linc/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Further information here.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
