<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automation, NLP, ML | Academic</title>
    <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/tag/automation-nlp-ml/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ihshaish.github.io/tag/automation-nlp-ml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Automation, NLP, ML</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ihshaish.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Automation, NLP, ML</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/tag/automation-nlp-ml/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automation in Construction</title>
      <link>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ihshaish.github.io/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Innovate UK £1.2M funding to explore the application of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning for Infrastructure Project Performance Benchmarking — &lt;strong&gt;Co-PI leading the AI and ML team and development&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research shows us that up to half of the money invested in infrastructure delivery could be spent more efficiently. Determined to increase the productivity and value-for-money of transport infrastructure projects, a transformative collaboration of 25 partners together with Government, i3P and the Construction Innovation Hub formed TIES Living Lab.
Using data, technology and Modern Methods of Construction (MMC) within live transport infrastructure projects, the TIES Living Lab will deliver significant value-adding benefits across the transport infrastructure sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results of our first models to automate project benchmarking are provided in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ihshaish.github.io/publication/icms-preprint/&#34;&gt;our preprint&lt;/a&gt;. Models have been trained and systematically evaluated from a dataset of more than 50 thousand descriptions of items retrieved from 24 large infrastructure construction (Highways England) projects across the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
